<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>DC Metro Real Estate Podcast with Jeff Wheatley</title>
    <link>localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Jeff Wheatley Homes - your professional DC Metro Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Jeff Wheatley</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-06-11 16:00:54 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Jeff Wheatley</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Jeff@JeffWheatleyHomes.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Jeff Wheatley</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Jeff Wheatley</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the DC Metro Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Jeff Wheatley Homes - your professional DC Metro Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Point-By-Point Guide to Winning a Multiple-Offer Situation</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-point-by-point-guide-to-winning-a-multiple-offer-situation.html</link>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Jeff Wheatley</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-08 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’d like to talk about multiple offers and the formula that will help you, the buyer, win in these kinds of scenarios. 

No matter if you’re in a multiple-offer situation or not, it’s important to develop an understanding of the psychology of the seller. Once this is established, you’ll want to go straight to the listing agent and pick their brain for more information on the needs of the seller they’re representing—the ‘seller’s needs’ analysis, as we like to call it. You can then determine how their needs parallel your own and craft an offer around that, which is sure to produce a win-win deal.   

After gaining insight into the seller’s needs, write a clean offer by following three steps: 


  Write a letter or shoot a video that pulls at the seller’s heartstrings. Doing this allows you to give a heartfelt explanation as to why owning the home would mean the world to you and your family. 
  Put together a clean summary page. Too often, the summary page of an offer we receive is crowded and the terms are buried deep in the document. Draft a well-organized, straightforward summary page, so the seller knows exactly what your terms are.
  Make sure the offer is complete. Frequently, small items or terms are absent from the offer, which only does a disservice to its overall presentation. Cover all the bases in your offer.


“Determine how the seller’s needs parallel your own and craft an offer around that to produce a win-win deal.”

Next, you should work with an agent from an “icon” team. That team should be known by the larger real estate community for its sterling reputation and serving the community as well as having good relationships with other Realtors. Your agent and their team should have “icon” status in four areas: 


  Credibility 
  The lender 
  The appraiser 
  The title agent


Fourth, try to combine contingencies when writing your offer. Wherever possible, condense two, three, or even four contingencies into one. This too makes for a cleaner, more organized presentation. 

Also, get creative with your earnest money deposit. There are a few different actions you can take such as raising your deposit as high as or above market value or putting forth multiple deposits—a smaller amount at the outset and, within 10 days, a larger amount.    

Finally, try to line up the closing date with the funding date, so it works for all parties. For example, everything will run much smoother if your lender can fast-track the closing process and get the deal done in, say, 10 to 12 days, as opposed to the market’s standard 30 days. A seller is more apt to accept an offer of this nature than one that will sit out there for 30 or 40 days before you have the available funds.              

If you have any questions about today’s topic or anything else real estate-related, please reach out to me. I’d be happy to help! 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’d like to talk about multiple offers and the formula that will help you, the buyer, win in these kinds of scenarios...</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jeff Wheatley</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’d like to talk about multiple offers and the formula that will help you, the buyer, win in these kinds of scenarios...</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Get a Better Return on Marketing Messages</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/how-to-get-a-better-return-on-marketing-messages.html</link>
        
        <author>Jeff Wheatley</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-30 09:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

About a month ago, a seasoned agent came to me because he was concerned about the lack of return from his inside sales program. After asking him a few questions, I quickly understood why this issue had come about. His inside sales agent team didn’t have a defined target audience, let alone a defined message. 

To help him fix these issues, I sat down and drew a simple diagram just like the one you can see in today’s video. This diagram, which is essentially a “marketing pyramid” is designed to help agents develop clear and purposeful marketing strategies. 

At the top of the pyramid is the word “who.” This prompt is meant to guide agents to think about what their ideal audience should be. In the case of the agent I mentioned earlier, for example, the best target audience for his message was senior citizens. 

“When an inside sales team follows these prompts to develop a marketing plan, while always keeping the desired outcome in mind, you’re sure to see a much higher return.”

In the middle of the pyramid, there’s the word “what.” Once you’ve determined who you’re sending your message to, you need to nail down what your message will be and what benefits it will offer. Again using the example of the agent I recently spoke with, we ultimately decided that his marketing message should focus on services, opportunities, and resources related to senior living options. 

Finally, the bottom of the pyramid consists of the words “how” and “medium.” These words represent the question “How will the inside sales agents deliver this message, and what medium will they use?” The way you deliver a marketing message, as well as the various materials and methods you use to send it out, will all have an impact on how it’s received. If you want to reach seniors, specifically, social media marketing will likely be less effective than direct mailers or another, more traditional method.

When an inside sales team follows these prompts to develop a marketing plan, while always keeping the desired outcome in mind, you’re sure to see a much higher return than if they implemented a more random approach. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What steps must an inside sales team follow to craft an effective marketing message? Let’s discuss this question today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jeff Wheatley</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What steps must an inside sales team follow to craft an effective marketing message? Let’s discuss this question today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Rockville, MD Real Estate Agent: Interview | Jeff's Story</title>
        <link>localhost:4000/rockville-md-real-estate-agent-interview-jeffs-story.html</link>
        
        <author>Jeff Wheatley</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-14 15:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Hear how Jeff Wheatley built his real estate business in Rockville, his tips for success, and his goals for the future.


</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Hear how Jeff Wheatley built his real estate business in Rockville, his tips for success, and his goals for the future.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Jeff Wheatley</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Hear how Jeff Wheatley built his real estate business in Rockville, his tips for success, and his goals for the future.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in DC Metro, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Jeff Wheatley</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Jeff Wheatley</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Jeff Wheatley Homes - your professional DC Metro Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
